Midnight in Paris is a fantasy, comedy, romance film directed by Woody Allen.
While on a trip to Paris with his fiancée's family, a nostalgic screenwriter finds
himself mysteriously going back to the 1920s every day at midnight.
Gil, played by Owen Wilson.
Inez, played by Rachel McAdams.
Gertrude Stein, played by Kathy Bates.
John, played by Kurt Fuller.
Salvador Dalí, played by Adrien Brody.
Museum Guide, played by Carla Bruni.
Midnight in Paris is a 2011 fantasy comedy film
written and directed by Woody Allen.
Set in Paris, the film follows Gil Pender (Owen Wilson), a screenwriter and aspiring novelist, who is forced to confront the shortcomings of his relationship with his
materialistic fiancée (Rachel McAdams) and their divergent goals, which become increasingly exaggerated as he travels back in time to the 1920s each night at midnight.
Produced by the Spanish group Mediapro and Allen's US-based Gravier Productions, the film stars Wilson, McAdams, Kathy Bates, Adrien Brody,
Carla Bruni, Tom Hiddleston, Corey Stoll, Alison Pill, Kurt Fuller, Mimi Kennedy, Lea Seydoux, Marion Cotillard, and Michael Sheen.
It premiered at the 2011 Cannes Film Festival and was
released in the United States on May 20, 2011.
The film opened to critical acclaim.
In 2012, it won the Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay
and the Golden Globe Award for Best Screenplay.
It was nominated for three other Academy Awards: Best
Picture, Best Director and Best Art Direction.
The film explores themes of paris, france, based on novel
or book, detective, screenwriter, camping.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.